MOHAMMED RAIF DATA ANALYST

Dubai, UAE | Mob: +971529653750 | Email: raif.kob@gmail.com

Portfolio Website: https://raiftheanalyst.netlify.app
LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/mohammedraif

Career Objective:

Team Leader with over 6 years of experience switching to a career as a **Data Analyst**. My education and practice on various projects are the foundation for my skills and abilities within analytical field. It helps me execute data analysis process, and meet the expectations of stake holders by giving beneficial insights.

Worked on a few projects and have a deep interest in managing large datasets, cleaning and manipulating data and creating compelling storytelling visualization using various tools.

Experience:

Freelancing

Oct 2022 - Present | Dubai, UAE

Team Leader - Sales & Customer Service, *Jumbo, Du Franchisee*

Dec 2019 - Jul 2022 | Abu Dhabi, UAE

Preparing reports, inventory purchase orders, analysing sales statistics and team performance using Excel to ensure all major KPIs are met. Extracting and analysing queue data to manage customer waiting and service time. Responsible for overseeing the daily operations of the store.

Membership Consultant, Gold's Gym Jul 2017 – Jul 2019 | Dubai, UAE

Sales Executive, *Emballage Trading* Oct 2015 – Feb 2017 | Dubai, UAE

Education:

- Google Data Analytics Certification,
 Coursera, September 2022
- Master of Business Administration,
 Dayananda College of Engineering
 2012 2014 | Bangalore, India
- Bachelors of Business Administration,
 Anjuman Institute of Management
 2009 2012 | Bhatkal, India

Technical Skills:

- SQL
- Big Query
- R-Programming
- Spreadsheet MS Excel, Google Sheets
- Power BI Power Query, DAX
- Tableau
- Python
- CRM

Soft Skills:

- Data-driven decision-making
- Excellent communicating and presenting skills
- Focused, organized, flexible and hardworking
- Creative, detail-oriented and able to work under pressure
- Research and Problem-Solving skills

Projects:

- Cyclistic Case Study: Drew Insights on how annual members and casual riders use Cyclistic bikes differently using Excel, R and Tableau.
- Airbnb Project: Avg Pricing and Revenue as per Zip codes using data visualisation tool -Tableau.
- Tata Data Visualisation: Empowering Business with Effective Insights virtual experience programme, virtual internship program by theforage.com
- Sales Performance Analysis: Extracted, analysed and created dashboard using MS -Excel.

Achievements:

- Promoted to Team Leader,
- Jumbo, Du Franchisee
- Outstanding Performer, Golds Gym
- Highest Sales Achiever, Golds Gym
- Employee of the Month, Golds Gym